<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Go - Tag - cuffaro.com</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/go/</link>
        <description>Go - Tag - cuffaro.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 08:00:47 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/go/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Speeding up a Go cli application with concurrency</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2023-03-20-go-concurrency/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 08:00:47 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>xxxx</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023-03-20-go-concurrency/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="premise">Premise</h2>
<p>A few months ago I worked with a company which provided fully functional backend for online multiplayer games.
As part of their product portfolio, they provided their customers with a cli utility, called <code>ds-uploader</code> (dedicated server uploader).</p>
<p>Written in Go, this CLI helped the customer:</p>
<ul>
<li>Process all files and assets in a directory of their choice containing their game server.</li>
<li>Synchronize each file to a remote object storage bucket (meaning to upload only files that are new or modified).</li>
<li>From those uploaded files, build a container image.</li>
<li>Pass that container image to another service, which would then be responsible to run it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Most of the implementation details involved calling different services, both belonging to the service provider, and to the cloud provider of choice (in this case, AWS).</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Pitfalls I encountered while learning Go</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2019-05-08-go-pitfalls/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 20:56:19 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>xxxx</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019-05-08-go-pitfalls/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I started learning Go on and off out of curiosity, late last year.</p>
<p>Being mainly a Python developer, I figured learning a different programming language would help to broaden my horizons.</p>
<p>Recently though, we adopted the language for some work projects, therefore I took the plunge and got to really hacking around with it.</p>
<p>The following are some noobie gotchas that I bumped into during development of my latest project (link below).
Mostly these came around while trying to figure out how to use mocks and asserts in unit tests with the <a href="https://github.com/stretchr/testify" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">testify</a> collection of packages.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
