<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Kubernetes - Tag - cuffaro.com</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/kubernetes/</link>
        <description>Kubernetes - Tag - cuffaro.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 08:42:47 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/kubernetes/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>My experience passing Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS) exam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2022-03-20-cks-experience/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 08:42:47 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>xxxx</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022-03-20-cks-experience/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Earlier in 2021, right after taking the exams for CKA and CKAD in succession (the experience of which I documented <a href="https://cuffaro.com/blog/2021-01-24-cka-ckad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">here</a>), I quickly booked the brand-new (at least at the time) CKS exam. Life happened, and I&rsquo;ve ended up procrastinating the study and preparation process until now 😅.</p>
<p>Today I got the great news of a PASS, and once again I would like to share my experience in obtaining this tough certification.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My experience passing CKA and CKAD</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021-01-24-cka-ckad/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:42:47 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>xxxx</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021-01-24-cka-ckad/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In December last year I was able to sit for the coveted Certified Kubernetes Administrator and Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exams, and clear them both after some preparation.</p>
<p>This post is meant to share my exam experience, and all the materials used.</p>
<h3 id="tldr">TL;DR</h3>
<ul>
<li>Read the exam questions carefully.</li>
<li>Know imperative commands with <code>kubectl</code> like the back of your hand.</li>
<li>Get comfortable looking things up on <a href="https://kubernetes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">kubernetes.io</a>.</li>
<li>Build a bookmark folder in Chrome with relevant pages in kubernetes.io: you can use it during the exam!</li>
<li>Seriously, read the damn questions carefully.</li>
<li>Practice, practice and practice more.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-exams">The exams</h3>
<p>The exam for any of these Kubernetes certifications consists in solving a set of tasks, in a 2 hour terminal session.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
