<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - cuffaro.com</title>
        <link>https://cuffaro.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | cuffaro.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>m@cuffaro.com (mike)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>m@cuffaro.com (mike)</webMaster><copyright>© {year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 08:42:47 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cuffaro.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>My experience passing Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS) exam</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2022-03-20-cks-experience/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 08:42:47 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2022-03-20-cks-experience/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Earlier in 2021, right after taking the exams for CKA and CKAD in succession (the experience of which I documented here), I quickly booked the brand-new (at least at the time) CKS exam. Life happened, and I&rsquo;ve ended up procrastinating the study and preparation process until now 😅.
Today I got the great news of a PASS, and once again I would like to share my experience in obtaining this tough certification.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My experience passing CKA and CKAD</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2021-01-24-cka-ckad/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:42:47 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2021-01-24-cka-ckad/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In December last year I was able to sit for the coveted Certified Kubernetes Administrator and Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exams, and clear them both after some preparation.
This post is meant to share my exam experience, and all the materials used.
TL;DR Read the exam questions carefully. Know imperative commands with kubectl like the back of your hand. Get comfortable looking things up on kubernetes.io. Build a bookmark folder in Chrome with relevant pages in kubernetes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Easy workflow for switching Python virtual environments</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2019-09-22-zsh-jump-workon/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 20:44:43 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2019-09-22-zsh-jump-workon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The problem I set out to solve was simply to avoid manually typing pyenv/venv commands when moving into directories containing different projects, and around my directory tree.
If you are like me, you would be working on different things at different times, and switching projects around seamlessly becomes a requirement to avoid waste of time, attention and context.
My environment For the sake of clarity, I am using a Macbook Pro with macOS Mojave, and I have iTerm2 set up with ZSH and oh-my-zsh as my shell.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Pitfalls I encountered while learning Go</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2019-05-08-go-pitfalls/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 20:56:19 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2019-05-08-go-pitfalls/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I started learning Go on and off out of curiosity, late last year.
Being mainly a Python developer, I figured learning a different programming language would help to broaden my horizons.
Recently though, we adopted the language for some work projects, therefore I took the plunge and got to really hacking around with it.
The following are some noobie gotchas that I bumped into during development of my latest project (link below).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Things I learned during my first year as a Junior Developer</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2019-02-11-things-i-learned-first-year-dev/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:42:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2019-02-11-things-i-learned-first-year-dev/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It&rsquo;s been an interesting 2018: it was the first year I have coded full-time while getting also paid for it. Before that, I worked mainly as internal IT support for a couple different companies, where my coding skills weren&rsquo;t being tested as much as right now.
I won&rsquo;t lie, the year wasn&rsquo;t always easy. I am surrounded by some brilliant people and I have very often felt some sort of inferiority complex that brought me down many a times; I thought that my experience (or lack thereof) was slowing down the team or not allowing us to achieve the goals we were supposed to achieve.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Making pyenv and neovim play nice (and a few gotchas found along the way)</title>
    <link>https://cuffaro.com/2018-04-16-pyenv-neovim/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 19:37:10 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>mike</author>
    <guid>https://cuffaro.com/2018-04-16-pyenv-neovim/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[For my development workflow and IDE, I&rsquo;ve recently decided to move from Vim, to NeoVim, which is essentially Vim on steroids.
No, but seriously, NeoVim has a few features that are really interesting, but the real reason for moving is that, as a Python dev, I need to be able to look at source code and definitions very often, while hacking on my code. The wonderful jedi-vim plugin normally allows me to do just that, when it comes to my local project.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
